<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>
  <status>success</status>
  <result>
    <project>
      <id>20446</id>
      <name>io-tools</name>
      <url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/io-tools.xml</url>
      <html_url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/io-tools</html_url>
      <created_at>2008-10-07T13:10:57Z</created_at>
      <updated_at>2013-06-23T23:57:07Z</updated_at>
      <description>Stream Utilities (EasyStream)Small set of utilities for dealing with streams. You can use this library for: 

'Convert' an OutputStream into an InputStream. Stream statistics gathering: bytes read/written, bit rate. Stream buffering: read the content of an InputStream multiple times or seek to a definite position. Stream wiring: While reading the data from an InputStream &quot;tee&quot; it to supplied OutputStream(s) or write data to multiple OutputStream(s) at the same time. EasyStream is a natural extension of Apache commons-io, providing advanced solutions to some common but not trivial problem. Focus is on performance and memory usage.  

Format detection (WazFormat)This library is a format identification framework that integrates a native format identification engine with droid and in future will integrate mime-utils and apache tika. 

Supports more than 60 file formats. on the fly detection: it wraps the original InputStream so it's able to &quot;preserve&quot; the data in it for further processing (the data is eventually buffered to disk or to memory but the users won't notice it). Nested detection: it can detect what is inside a bzip2 stream or a PKCS#7 document. Result of identification is an Enum. Most of identification libraries return a string that must be further parsed by the calling software. What is next ?Take the 5 minutes tutorials:  'Convert' an OutputStream into an InputStream introduction stream utilities explained usage. format identification. Check out the full API (Javadoc) at easystream and wazformat .  Download the latest version (see the link on the right) or if you're a Maven2 user install it (if you use Maven2 you'll get the freshest but stable version). Post your questions on the users forum. 

Any help is appreciated (also comment or suggestion or bug reports). If you want to contribute please contact me through the forum and request for a membership.</description>
      <homepage_url>http://code.google.com/p/io-tools</homepage_url>
      <download_url>http://code.google.com/p/io-tools/downloads/list</download_url>
      <url_name>io-tools</url_name>
      <medium_logo_url>http://cloud.ohloh.net/attachments/39663/i-o.ico_med.png</medium_logo_url>
      <small_logo_url>http://cloud.ohloh.net/attachments/39663/i-o.ico_small.png</small_logo_url>
      <user_count>2</user_count>
      <average_rating>5.0</average_rating>
      <rating_count>2</rating_count>
      <review_count>0</review_count>
      <analysis_id>14368331</analysis_id>
      <tags>
        <tag>inputstream</tag>
        <tag>java</tag>
        <tag>mime</tag>
        <tag>readinputstreammultipletimes</tag>
        <tag>library</tag>
        <tag>outputstream</tag>
        <tag>wiring</tag>
        <tag>detection</tag>
        <tag>pipe</tag>
        <tag>format</tag>
        <tag>streamutilities</tag>
      </tags>
      <analysis>
        <id>14368331</id>
        <url>http://www.ohloh.net/analyses/14368331.xml</url>
        <project_id>20446</project_id>
        <updated_at>2013-07-13T09:09:10Z</updated_at>
        <logged_at>2013-07-13T09:06:07Z</logged_at>
        <min_month>2008-11-01T00:00:00Z</min_month>
        <max_month>2013-01-01T00:00:00Z</max_month>
        <twelve_month_contributor_count>1</twelve_month_contributor_count>
        <total_code_lines>14246</total_code_lines>
        <factoids>
          <factoid type="FactoidActivityIncreasing">
Increasing Y-O-Y development activity          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidAgeOld">
Well-established codebase          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidCommentsHigh">
Well-commented source code          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidTeamSizeOne">
Only a single active developer          </factoid>
        </factoids>
        <languages graph_url="http://www.ohloh.net/p/io-tools/analyses/14368331/languages.png">
          <language color="9A63AD" percentage="76" id="5">
Java          </language>
          <language color="555555" percentage="19" id="3">
XML          </language>
          <language color="000000" percentage="5" id="">
2 Other          </language>
        </languages>
        <main_language_id>5</main_language_id>
        <main_language_name>Java</main_language_name>
      </analysis>
      <licenses>
        <license>
          <name>bsd</name>
          <nice_name>BSD 4-clause (University of California-Specific)</nice_name>
        </license>
      </licenses>
    </project>
  </result>
</response>
