<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>
  <status>success</status>
  <result>
    <project>
      <id>48277</id>
      <name>metastudio</name>
      <url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/metastudio.xml</url>
      <html_url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/metastudio</html_url>
      <created_at>2008-12-16T07:04:04Z</created_at>
      <updated_at>2013-07-05T18:34:30Z</updated_at>
      <description>MeTA Studio is programmable IDE tailored for a computational chemist.  Main features include: 

A programmable interface primarily through BeanShell with support for  other languages Workspace support Visualization and Rendering (through JRman) Support for 3-D scalar field visualization Access to embedded Jmol and its libraries Access to parts or modifications of quantumj and mathutils libraries (hosted on java.net) for Quantum Chemical calculations A peer-to-peer networking interface for grouping instances of MeTA studio running on multiple machines to perform varied tasks including computation, rendering and collaboration To be included: 

A new Mathematica type interface tailored for computational chemistry A collaborative environment for interaction among computational chemists working on similar problems Ahead in future: 

MeTA Studio is not meant to be restricted for use in Computational Chemistry domain, although currently it is more focused towards it. I expect many frameworks in MeTA Studio to expand on to other computational science(s) in near future, with hopefully strong contributions from experts in other fields. I envisage MeTA Studio to be a complete platform for doing computational science, whether it be as a tool, as a programming platform for building new scientific applications, or even as a teaching aid. Installation and other information: 

For installation instructions check http://code.google.com/p/metastudio/wiki/Installation.  Also check http://code.google.com/p/metastudio/wiki/ for general help articles on various topics related to MeTA Studio. For latest updates and screen shots check out my blog at http://tovganesh.blogspot.com/search/label/MeTA Latest Version: 2.0.04062009 Online Update Release Date: (None at the moment, upgrade to latest binary release) Full Binary Release Date: 4 June, 2009 Stable Source Tarball Release Date: 14 January, 2009 Daily source update (SVN access): http://code.google.com/p/metastudio/source/browse/ To get involved check: How you can help News! Happy to say that a report describing MeTA Studio is published in J. Comput. Chem. (Volume 30, Pages 661 - 672, 2009). I hope that this brings in more developers and users for the MeTA Studio platform! 

Citation 

If you use MeTA Studio in a research publication, you may cite the following: 


&quot;MeTA studio: A cross platform, programmable IDE for computational chemist&quot;, V. Ganesh, J. Comput. Chem., 30, 661 (2009). (Web: http://code.google.com/p/metastudio/) 
Ohloh Stats: 

.gadget-title {
  margin-bottom: 2px;
}



function resizeIframeHandler(opt_height) {
  var elem = document.getElementById(this.f);
  if (!elem) return;
  if (!opt_height) {
    elem.style.height = undefined;
  }
  else {
    opt_height = Math.max(10, opt_height);
    elem.style.height = opt_height + 'px';
  }
}
gadgets.rpc.register(&quot;resize_iframe&quot;, resizeIframeHandler);

gadgets.rpc.register('set_title', function(title) {
 var elem = document.getElementById(this.f + '_title');
 if (elem) {
   elem.innerHTML = gadgets.util.escape(title);
 }
});</description>
      <homepage_url>http://code.google.com/p/metastudio</homepage_url>
      <download_url></download_url>
      <url_name>metastudio</url_name>
      <medium_logo_url>no_logo.png</medium_logo_url>
      <small_logo_url>no_logo.png</small_logo_url>
      <user_count>4</user_count>
      <average_rating>5.0</average_rating>
      <rating_count>1</rating_count>
      <review_count>0</review_count>
      <analysis_id>14540004</analysis_id>
      <tags>
        <tag>ide</tag>
        <tag>java</tag>
        <tag>computationalchemistry</tag>
      </tags>
      <analysis>
        <id>14540004</id>
        <url>http://www.ohloh.net/analyses/14540004.xml</url>
        <project_id>48277</project_id>
        <updated_at>2013-07-05T18:34:29Z</updated_at>
        <logged_at>2013-07-05T18:34:11Z</logged_at>
        <min_month>2009-03-01T00:00:00Z</min_month>
        <max_month>2013-01-01T00:00:00Z</max_month>
        <twelve_month_contributor_count>1</twelve_month_contributor_count>
        <total_code_lines>252165</total_code_lines>
        <factoids>
          <factoid type="FactoidCommentsHigh">
Well-commented source code          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidAgeOld">
Well-established codebase          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidTeamSizeOne">
Only a single active developer          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidActivityDecreasing">
Decreasing Y-O-Y development activity          </factoid>
        </factoids>
        <languages graph_url="http://www.ohloh.net/p/metastudio/analyses/14540004/languages.png">
          <language color="9A63AD" percentage="92" id="5">
Java          </language>
          <language color="555555" percentage="7" id="3">
XML          </language>
          <language color="000000" percentage="1" id="">
6 Other          </language>
        </languages>
        <main_language_id>5</main_language_id>
        <main_language_name>Java</main_language_name>
      </analysis>
      <licenses>
        <license>
          <name>lgpl</name>
          <nice_name>GNU Library or &quot;Lesser&quot; GPL (LGPL)</nice_name>
        </license>
      </licenses>
    </project>
  </result>
</response>
