<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>
  <status>success</status>
  <result>
    <project>
      <id>47858</id>
      <name>swordbible</name>
      <url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/swordbible.xml</url>
      <html_url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/swordbible</html_url>
      <created_at>2008-12-16T05:59:50Z</created_at>
      <updated_at>2013-07-17T10:55:21Z</updated_at>
      <description>A simple, free and powerful electronic bible study software for windows with hundreds of bibles, commentaries, daily devotions and dictionaries. It can be downloaded and used forever for free. It is based on the sword engine by CrossWire Bible Society.The SWORD Project is the CrossWire Bible Society&#8217;s free Bible software project. Its purpose is to create cross-platform open-source tools&#8211; covered by the GNU General Public License&#8211; that allow programmers and Bible societies to write new Bible software more quickly and easily. Its secondary purpose is to amass a library of Bibles and other Scripture related texts that can be used by all SWORD Project-based software. Sword Bible has numerous other features: 

Search for a particular word or phrase in the entire bible or commentary. Store personal bookmarks and create your personal notes/commentary using a rich text editor Hide or display footnotes, cross-references, red letter words, lemma and morphological tags  Compare verses from different bibles using parallel columns  Verse Lists feature supports creating personalized lists, and adding or removing verses from them. SwordBible comes pre-loaded with verses in 115 different categories Create daily reading plans to study the bible in a month or a year,keeping track of your progress as you go along For more information, please visit the project homepage at SwordBible 

Got a question? Ask at Google Discussion group</description>
      <homepage_url>http://code.google.com/p/swordbible</homepage_url>
      <download_url></download_url>
      <url_name>swordbible</url_name>
      <medium_logo_url>no_logo.png</medium_logo_url>
      <small_logo_url>no_logo_32.png</small_logo_url>
      <user_count>2</user_count>
      <average_rating></average_rating>
      <rating_count>0</rating_count>
      <review_count>0</review_count>
      <analysis_id>14661858</analysis_id>
      <tags>
        <tag>bible</tag>
        <tag>kjv</tag>
        <tag>ebible</tag>
        <tag>sword</tag>
        <tag>niv</tag>
      </tags>
      <analysis>
        <id>14661858</id>
        <url>http://www.ohloh.net/analyses/14661858.xml</url>
        <project_id>47858</project_id>
        <updated_at>2013-07-17T10:55:21Z</updated_at>
        <logged_at>2013-07-17T10:55:14Z</logged_at>
        <min_month>2009-03-01T00:00:00Z</min_month>
        <max_month>2009-03-01T00:00:00Z</max_month>
        <twelve_month_contributor_count>0</twelve_month_contributor_count>
        <total_code_lines>19853</total_code_lines>
        <factoids>
          <factoid type="FactoidAgeYoung">
Short source control history          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidCommentsAverage">
Average number of code comments          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidActivityStable">
Stable Y-O-Y development activity          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidTeamSizeZero">
No recent development activity          </factoid>
        </factoids>
        <languages graph_url="http://www.ohloh.net/p/swordbible/analyses/14661858/languages.png">
          <language color="F35F1F" percentage="91" id="44">
C++          </language>
          <language color="000000" percentage="9" id="">
3 Other          </language>
        </languages>
        <main_language_id>44</main_language_id>
        <main_language_name>C++</main_language_name>
      </analysis>
      <licenses>
        <license>
          <name>gpl</name>
          <nice_name>GNU General Public License v2.0 or later</nice_name>
        </license>
      </licenses>
    </project>
  </result>
</response>
