<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>
  <status>success</status>
  <result>
    <project>
      <id>55723</id>
      <name>lua-alchemy</name>
      <url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/lua-alchemy.xml</url>
      <html_url>http://www.ohloh.net/p/lua-alchemy</html_url>
      <created_at>2008-12-17T05:48:30Z</created_at>
      <updated_at>2013-06-26T01:41:16Z</updated_at>
      <description>IntroductionBackgroundLua is a great dynamic programming language, Adobe Flash is a great universal platform for applications and Adobe Alchemy is the tool to bind them together. 

A demo can be found here: http://lua-alchemy.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/demo/index.html 

Can you help us? 

LuaLua is a powerful, fast, light-weight, embeddable scripting language. 
Lua combines simple procedural syntax with powerful data description constructs based on associative arrays and extensible semantics. Lua is dynamically typed, runs by interpreting bytecode for a register-based virtual machine, and has automatic memory management with incremental garbage collection, making it ideal for configuration, scripting, and rapid prototyping. 
-- http://lua.org/about.html 
Adobe FlashAdobe Flash (previously called &quot;Macromedia Flash&quot;') is a set of multimedia software created by Macromedia and currently developed and distributed by Adobe Systems. Since its introduction in 1996, Flash has become a popular method for adding animation and interactivity to web pages; Flash is commonly used to create animation, advertisements, and various web page components, to integrate video into web pages, and more recently, to develop rich Internet applications. 
-- http://en.wikipedia.com/wiki/Flash 
Adobe AlchemyWith Alchemy, Web application developers can now reuse hundreds of millions of lines of existing open source C and C++ client or server-side code on the Flash Platform.  Alchemy brings the power of high performance C and C++ libraries to Web applications with minimal degradation on AVM2.  The C/C++ code is compiled to ActionScript 3.0 as a SWF or SWC that runs on Adobe Flash Player 10 or Adobe AIR 1.5. 
    

-- http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/alchemy/ 


MotivationWe need Lua Alchemy to... 

...To use run-time dynamic programming language (Lua) within the Flash framework.  ...To reuse existing Lua code for the Flash-based utilities ...To get a great cross-platform back-end (Flash) for (simpler) Lua-based games ...To have fun with awesome new technology :-) OrganizationSitesMain place for collaboration: GoogleProjects (file releases, wiki, issues) Main place for development: GitHub (Git source control) Developer's mailing list: GoogleGroups (to be made open for public as soon as we're ready) LicenseLua Achemy is licensed at the same license as Lua 5.1: the MIT license. This means that Lua Alchemy is free software and can be used for both academic and commercial purposes at absolutely no cost. 

See alsoLuaToAs3Interface InitialFileReleases FeatureWishList KnownProblems RandomNotes RecommendedReading ToDo LuaAlchemyDevelopmentModel</description>
      <homepage_url>http://code.google.com/p/lua-alchemy</homepage_url>
      <download_url></download_url>
      <url_name>lua-alchemy</url_name>
      <medium_logo_url>no_logo.png</medium_logo_url>
      <small_logo_url>no_logo_32.png</small_logo_url>
      <user_count>2</user_count>
      <average_rating>5.0</average_rating>
      <rating_count>1</rating_count>
      <review_count>0</review_count>
      <analysis_id>14410743</analysis_id>
      <tags>
        <tag>flex</tag>
        <tag>lua</tag>
        <tag>flash</tag>
        <tag>actionscript</tag>
        <tag>alchemy</tag>
      </tags>
      <analysis>
        <id>14410743</id>
        <url>http://www.ohloh.net/analyses/14410743.xml</url>
        <project_id>55723</project_id>
        <updated_at>2013-07-16T06:09:21Z</updated_at>
        <logged_at>2013-07-16T06:09:20Z</logged_at>
        <min_month>2008-12-01T00:00:00Z</min_month>
        <max_month>2012-03-01T00:00:00Z</max_month>
        <twelve_month_contributor_count>0</twelve_month_contributor_count>
        <total_code_lines>28464</total_code_lines>
        <factoids>
          <factoid type="FactoidAgeOld">
Well-established codebase          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidCommentsLow">
Few source code comments          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidActivityDecreasing">
Decreasing Y-O-Y development activity          </factoid>
          <factoid type="FactoidTeamSizeZero">
No recent development activity          </factoid>
        </factoids>
        <languages graph_url="http://www.ohloh.net/p/lua-alchemy/analyses/14410743/languages.png">
          <language color="FF8F00" percentage="47" id="42">
C          </language>
          <language color="47A400" percentage="25" id="1">
HTML          </language>
          <language color="E3491A" percentage="16" id="53">
ActionScript          </language>
          <language color="000000" percentage="12" id="">
8 Other          </language>
        </languages>
        <main_language_id>42</main_language_id>
        <main_language_name>C</main_language_name>
      </analysis>
      <licenses>
        <license>
          <name>mit</name>
          <nice_name>MIT License</nice_name>
        </license>
      </licenses>
    </project>
  </result>
</response>
